Jessica Graham | UX Designer

London, UK

Phone: 07949405066

Email: jessicagraham898@gmail.com

Portfolio: jgraham898.github.io

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/jessica-graham-ux

I'm a UX designer with a graphic design degree and over 5 years of marketing experience, driving consistent growth across various KPIs in several international markets. I deliver strong, research-based UX solutions with measurable results. I'm passionate about empathetic, accessible and human-focused design that makes a real, positive impact on users.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

UX Designer | Freelance 2020 - Present

- Single-handedly delivered a complete app and website redesign for **The Tribe**, a platform for startup accelerator events.
- Conducting user research through methods such as contextual interviews, online surveys and questionnaires.
- Creating deliverables such as personas, affinity maps, user journey maps, user flow diagrams and wireframes using Figma/Sketch.
- Usability testing; iterating on design concepts using Design Thinking methodology.
- Communicating with developers and other stakeholders about translating my work into on-site changes.

Paid Search Specialist | STA Travel 2016 – 2020

I handled paid search marketing accounts across 3 international markets (UK, Australia and New Zealand) as part of the digital acquisitions team.

From 2019-2020, I increased year-on-year Google Ads ROI by 20% and click-through rate by 45%.

- Launching and optimising campaigns across Google Ads and Bing Ads.
- Creating monthly marketing plans, allocating budgets up to £200,000 per month.
- A/B testing and analysing performance data using Google Analytics 360.
- Reporting and consulting with stakeholders; educating stakeholders and colleagues about paid search through meetings and presentations.

Content Manager | DLH Web Consultancy 2013 – 2016

I began as the agency's sole content writer; was promoted to managing a team of 4 when more writers were recruited.

- Writing, proofreading and editing online content for small to medium sized businesses across many industries.
- Incorporating SEO strategies through use of metatags and keywords.
- Communicating with clients and making recommendations for their content strategies.

Content Writer | Business Search Local 2011 – 2013

 Writing website content, blogs and marketing materials for small to medium sized businesses across many industries.

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

- Various freelance content writing projects
- Various freelance illustration jobs
- Hospitality industry work cleaning, bartending, ticket collecting, running nightclub cloakrooms

EDUCATION

School of UX | 2020

CPD Certification - UX Design

Founders & Coders | 2019

Web Development Fundamentals short course

Northumbria University | 2007 – 2010

(BA Hons): Graphic Design

Cleveland College of Art & Design | 2005 – 2007

BTEC National Diploma: Graphic Design & Photography